blinkist.com 2018-06-30

# Privacy Policy

**Last updated: 24. May 2018**

**Our Privacy Policy in a nutshell**

The following notes give you an overview of how we collect and process your information. This is an overview, but if you want to know it exactly, you will find a detailed description here. 

**Data we collect about you**

On the one hand, your data is captured because you communicate it to us. This may, for example, be data that you enter in our contact form. Other data is collected automatically when visiting the website through our IT systems. These are above all technical data (eg Internet browser, operating system or time of the page request). The collection of this data is automatic as soon as you visit our platform. 

  * **Registration Information:** When you register for Blinkist (for our free offer, paid subscription, or use of a code), we collect the personal information that you voluntarily provide to us when registering through your access device. 
  * **Cookies:** For the provision of the Blinking service and to make our offer more user-friendly, effective and secure, we also use so-called cookies for data collection and storage. Cookies are small data packets that are stored on your device and do no harm. 
  * **Tracking Services:** We use tracking services to collect information about the behavior of visitors to our pages. So we can ensure an optimal user experience. These services use pseudonymised user profiles with the help of cookies, so that a direct inference to persons is not possible. Of course you can contradict the creation of these profiles at any time. Incidentally, each access device can be configured in such a way that basically no cookies can be created at all, or they can be deleted directly after the session. 
  * **Social Plugins:** Our pages contain buttons from various social networks so that you can recommend our offers, services and / or products to other interested people. If you click on such a button, data such as your current IP address, browser and access device information (type and operating system), the resolution of the screen, if you have plug-ins installed will be the referrer (from where you came to the site) and the current URL to the site operator. 
  * **Newsletter:** When you sign up for our newsletter, your e-mail address will be used for information on advertising and advertising purposes. Of course, this is voluntary and you can even after the consent at any time unsubscribe. 
  * **Payment Information:** If you use our free access, any of our trial phases or any of our subscriptions or you purchase anything through the Service, credit card information and other financial information we need to process the payment will be collected and stored with a payment service provider. We ourselves receive very little information from the payment providers about you. 

**How we collect your data**

We collect your data in three different ways: 

  * automated when you visit our website
  * through cookies 
  * through your voluntary input

### What we use your data for

We want to offer you a faultless use of our services. Therefore, data is needed for the administration and troubleshooting of our websites. However, as we are constantly improving ourselves and offering you optimized services, data in pseudonymised form (through usage profiles) are also needed for advertising and / or market research. Of course, this can be contradicted at any time. 

### How we work with partners

In some cases, your data is also processed by partner companies. However, this is exclusively regulated by data processing agreements and the processing is instruction-bound, so that we always keep the responsibility for the processing. 

### Use of your data for other purposes

In addition to the purposes already mentioned, we are also subject to legal requirements. These are:

  * any request for information (and the related disclosure) by governmental authorities
  * any request for information (and the related disclosure) by copyright holders
  * for the misuse recognition of our provided services
  * trouble-shooting or -avoidance

### Your rights as a user of our services

You have the right to information, correction, blocking or deletion of your data at any time. You can contact our data protection officer at any time for further information on privacy issues. Our data protection officer Thorsten Schröers can be reached either by post (HC Plus | Geneststraße 5 | D-10829 Berlin) or by e-mail (privacy@blinkist.com). 

## Our Privacy Policy in detail

### General and Responsible Entity

We are glad that you are interested in Blinkist. In order to provide you with our service, we need certain information about you (including personally identifiable information - information that identifies you personally). This Privacy Policy explains what information we collect about you for what purpose and what we use it for. It also explains how and for what purpose this happens. 

Blinks Labs GmbH, Sonnenallee 223, D-12059 Berlin (hereafter referred to as "Blinkist" or "we") operates on the internet portals http://www.blinkist.com, http://www.blinkist.de and other websites , as well as via the mobile application a platform for mobile learning (hereinafter "platform"). 

Responsible body is the natural or legal person who, alone or together with others, decides on the purposes and means of processing personal data (eg names, e-mail addresses, etc.). 

### Revocation of consent 

Many data processing operations are only possible with your express consent. You can revoke an existing consent at any time. An informal message by e-mail to us is sufficient. The legality of the data processing carried out until the revocation remains unaffected by the revocation. 

### Right to complain to the competent supervisory authority 

In the event of data protection violations, you, the person concerned, have the right of appeal to the competent supervisory authority. The competent supervisory authority for data protection issues is the state data protection officer of the federal state in which our company is based. A list of data protection officers and their contact details can be found [here](https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html). 

### SSL or TLS Encryption 

This site uses SSL or Internet security for security reasons and to protect the transmission of sensitive content, such as orders or requests you send to us. TLS encryption. An encrypted connection is indicated by the browser's address bar switching from "http: //" to "https: //" and the lock icon in your browser bar. 

If SSL or TLS encryption is enabled, the data you submit to us can not be read by third parties. 

### Information, Blocking, Deletion, Data Transferability

You have the right at any time to inquire about the origin, recipient and purpose of your stored personal data free of charge (information). In addition, you have the right to request the correction, blocking or deletion of this data. Our data protection officers are happy to assist you. 

You also have the right to have data, which we process on the basis of your consent or in fulfillment of a contract, automatically handed to you or to a third party in a standard, machine-readable format. If you want to transfer your data directly to another person in charge, this will only be done if we can make it technically possible. 

## Data collection and use 

### Server log files 

Our provider of the platform automatically collects and stores information in so-called server log files, which your browser automatically transmits to us. These are browser type and browser version, operating system used, referrer URL, host name of the accessing computer, time of the server request and the IP address. The data is for data security and error analysis only. A merge of this data with other data sources will not be done. The basis for data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. b DSGVO, which allows the processing of data to fulfill a contract or pre-contractual measures. 

Die Daten dienen ausschließlich der Datensicherheit und Fehleranalyse. Eine Zusammenführung dieser Daten mit anderen Datenquellen wird nicht vorgenommen.  
Grundlage für die Datenverarbeitung ist Art.6 Abs.1 lit. b DSGVO, der die Verarbeitung von Daten zur Erfüllung eines Vertrags oder vorvertraglicher Maßnahmen gestattet. 

### Cookies

The internet pages partly use so-called cookies. Cookies do not harm your access device and do not contain viruses. Cookies serve to make our offer more user-friendly, effective and secure. Cookies are small text files that are stored on your access device and stored by your browser. 

Most of the cookies we use are so-called "session cookies". They will be deleted automatically at the end of your visit. Other cookies remain stored on your device until you delete them. These cookies allow us to recognize your browser on your next visit. 

You can set your browser so that you are informed about the setting of cookies and allow cookies only in individual cases, exclude the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or in general, and enable the automatic deletion of cookies when closing the browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of our website. 

Cookies which are required to carry out the electronic communication process or to provide certain functions which you wish to use (eg shopping basket function) are processed on the basis of Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO saved. We as website operators have a legitimate interest in the storage of cookies for the technically error-free and optimized provision of our services. If other cookies (eg cookies for the analysis of your surfing behavior) are stored, they will be treated separately in this privacy policy. 

### Contact form and Zendesk

We use the Zendesk ticket system to handle customer inquiries, a customer service platform of Zendesk Inc., 989 Market Street #300, San Francisco, CA 94102 (USA). Zendesk is a certified participant of the so-called "Privacy Shield Framework" and thus meets the minimum requirements for legally compliant order data processing. 

For more information about Zendesk's data processing, please refer to the [Zendesk Privacy Policy](https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/). If you have questions, you can also contact the [Privacy Officer of Zendesk](mailto:privacy@zendesk.com) directly. 

If you send us inquiries via contact form or by using our public, non-personal e-mail addresses, your details from the inquiry form, including the contact details given there, will be stored with us for processing the request and in case of follow-up questions. We will not share this information without your consent. 

The processing of the data entered into the contact form is therefore exclusively based on your consent (Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR). You can revoke this consent at any time. An informal message by e-mail to us or our data protection officer is sufficient. The legality of the data processing operations carried out until the revocation remains unaffected by the revocation. 

The data entered by you in the contact form will remain with us until you request us to delete, revoke your consent to the storage or the purpose for the data storage is omitted (eg after completion of your request). Mandatory statutory provisions - especially retention periods - remain unaffected. 

### Registration on this website 

You can register on our platform to use our services. We only use the data entered for the purpose of using the respective offer for which you have registered. The mandatory information requested during registration, such as name and e-mail address, must be provided, otherwise the registration can not be completed. 

For important changes such as the scope of the offer or in case of technical changes, we use the e-mail address given at registration to inform you in this way. 

The processing of the data entered during registration takes place on the basis of your consent (Art.6 (1) (a) GDPR). You can revoke your consent at any time. An informal message by e-mail to us is sufficient. The legality of the already completed data processing remains unaffected by the revocation. 

The data collected during registration will be stored by us as long as you are registered for our services and will subsequently be deleted. Legal retention periods remain unaffected. 

### Registration and login with Facebook Connect

Instead of registering directly on our website, you can sign up with Facebook Connect. Provider of this service is the Facebook Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Dublin 2, Ireland. 

If you decide to register with Facebook Connect and click on the "Sign in with Facebook" button, you will automatically be redirected to the Facebook platform. There you can log in with your usage data. This links your Facebook profile to our website or services. This link gives us access to your data stored on Facebook. These are above all: 

Facebook name | Facebook profile and cover image | Email address stored at Facebook and Facebook ID 

Diese Daten werden zur Einrichtung, Bereitstellung und Personalisierung deines Accounts genutzt. 

This information is used to set up, provision and personalize your account. For more information, see the [Facebook Terms of Use](https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/) and the [Facebook Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). 

### Register and login with Google Connect

Instead of a direct registration / login on our website, you can also register via Google. Provider of this service is the Google LLC ("Google"), Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (USA). 

If you decide to register / login with Google and click the "Sign in with Google" button, you will automatically be redirected to Google's platform. There you can log in with your usage data. This will link your Google profile to our website or services. This link gives us access to your data stored on Google. These are above all: 

First name | Surname | E-mail address | Username | Google Profile URL | Featured Image 

This information is used to set up, provision and personalize your accounts. 

For more information, see the [Google Terms of Service](https://policies.google.com/terms) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). 

## Social Media

### Facebook plugins

On our pages plugins of the social network Facebook, provider Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California 94025 (USA), are integrated. The Facebook plug-ins can be recognized by the Facebook logo or the "Like-Button" ("Like") on our site. An overview of the Facebook plugins can be found [here](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/). 

When you visit our platform, a direct connection between your browser and the Facebook server is established via the plugin. Facebook receives the information that you have visited our site with your IP address. If you click on the Facebook "Like-Button" while you are logged in to your Facebook account, you can link the contents of our pages to your Facebook profile. This allows Facebook to associate your visit to our pages with your user account. We point out that we as the provider of the pages are not aware of the content of the data transmitted and their use by Facebook. More information can be found in the [privacy policy of Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/). 

If you do not want Facebook to associate visiting our pages with your Facebook user account, please log out of your Facebook user account. 

### Twitter plugin

On our pages are functions of the service Twitter included. These features are available through Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103 (USA). By using Twitter and the "Re-Tweet" function, the websites you visit are linked to your Twitter account and shared with other users. This data is also transmitted to Twitter. We point out that we as the provider of the pages are not aware of the content of the transmitted data and their use by Twitter. For more information, see the [privacy policy of Twitter](https://twitter.com/privacy). 

You can change your privacy settings on Twitter in the [Twitter account settings](https://twitter.com/account/settings). 

### Google+ plugin

Our pages use features of Google. Provider is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (USA). 

Collect and share information: Use the Google button to post information worldwide. The Google button will provide you and other users with personalized content from Google and our partners. Google stores both the information that you provided for content +1 and information about the page that you viewed when you clicked on+ 1. Your 1's can appear as clues along with your profile name and photo on Google's services, such as in search results or in your Google profile, or elsewhere on websites and ads on the web. 

Google records information about your +1 activity to improve Google services for you and others. To use the Google button, you'll need a globally visible, public Google profile that has at least the name chosen for the profile. This name will be used in all Google services. In some cases, this name may also replace another name you used when sharing content through your Google Account. The identity of your Google profile can be viewed by users who know your email address or have other identifying information about you. 

In addition to the purposes outlined above, the information you provide will be used in accordance with applicable Google privacy policy. Google may publish summarized statistics about users +1 activities or share them with users and partners, such as publishers, advertisers, or affiliate websites. 

### LinkedIn plugin

Our site uses functions from the LinkedIn network. The service is provided by LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. 

Each time one of our pages containing LinkedIn features is accessed, your browser establishes a direct connection to the LinkedIn servers. LinkedIn is informed that you have visited our web pages from your IP address. If you use the LinkedIn “Recommend” button and are logged into your LinkedIn account, it is possible for LinkedIn to associate your visit to our website to your user account. We would like to point out that, as the provider of these pages, we have no knowledge of the content of the data transmitted or how it will be used by LinkedIn. 

More information can be found in the [LinkedIn privacy policy ](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy). 

## Analysis tools and advertising 

### Google Analytics

This website uses functions of the web analytics service Google Analytics. Provider is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (USA). 

Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies". These are text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the United States and stored there. Google Analytics cookies are stored on the basis of Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

Here’re the details in regard to how we’re using Google Analytics: 

  * **IP anonymization:** We have activated the function IP anonymization on this website. As a result, your IP address will be truncated by Google within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area prior to transmission to the United States. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. The IP address provided by Google Analytics as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data.
  * **Browser plugin:** You can prevent the storage of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly; however, we point out that in this case you may not be able to use all the features of this website in full. In addition, you may prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address) as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under [this link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * **Opposition to data collection:** You can prevent the collection of your data by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. An opt-out cookie will be set that prevents the collection of your data on future visits to this website: disable Google Analytics. For more information about how to handle user data on Google Analytics, see the [Google Privacy Policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=de).
  * **Commissioned data processing:** We have entered into an order data processing contract with Google and fully implement the strict requirements of the German data protection authorities when using Google Analytics.
  * **Demographic data:** This website uses the "demographics" feature of Google Analytics. As a result, reports can be produced that contain statements on the age, gender and interests of the site visitors. This data comes from interest-based advertising from Google and third-party visitor data. This data can not be assigned to a specific person. You can disable this feature at any time through the Ads settings in your Google Account, or generally prohibit Google Analytics from collecting your data as outlined in the "Opposition to Data Collection" section.

### Google AdSense

This website uses Google AdSense, a service for integrating advertisements of Google Inc. ("Google"). Provider is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (USA).  
Google AdSense uses so-called "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website. Google AdSense also uses so-called web beacons (invisible graphics). These web beacons can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on these pages.  
The information generated by cookies and web beacons on the use of this website (including your IP address) and the delivery of advertising formats are transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the USA. This information may be shared by Google with Google affiliates. However, Google will not merge your IP address with other data you have stored.  
The storage of AdSense cookies is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising.  
You can prevent the installation of cookies by setting your browser accordingly; however, we point out that in this case you may not be able to fully use all features of this website. By using this website, you agree to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described above and for the purpose stated above. 

### Google Analytics Remarketing

Our websites use the features of Google Analytics Remarketing in conjunction with the cross-device features of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick. Provider is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (USA).  
This feature allows you to link the advertising audiences created with Google Analytics Remarketing to the cross-device capabilities of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick. In this way, interest-based, personalized advertising messages that have been adapted to you based on your previous usage and surfing behavior on one device (i.e. mobile phone) can also be displayed on another of your devices (i.e. tablet or PC).  
Once you have given your consent, Google will link your web and app browsing history to your Google Account for this purpose. That way, the same personalized advertising messages can appear on any device you sign in to with your Google Account.  
To support this feature, Google Analytics collects Google-authenticated IDs of users who are temporarily linked to our Google Analytics data to define and create audiences for cross-device ad promotion. You can permanently opt out of cross-device remarketing / targeting by disabling personalized ads in your Google Account; follow [this link](https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb).  
The aggregation of the collected data in your Google Account is based solely on your consent, which you can give or revoke on Google (Art.6 Abs.1 a. DSGVO). For data collection operations that are not merged into your Google Account (eg, because you do not have a Google Account or have objected to the merge), the collection of the data is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The legitimate interest arises from the fact that the website operator has an interest in the anonymous analysis of the website visitors for advertising purposes.  
For more information and privacy policy, see the [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads). 

### Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking

Tracking This website uses Google AdWords. AdWords is an online advertising program of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043 (USA) ("Google").  
As part of Google AdWords, we use the so-called conversion tracking. When you click on an ad served by Google, a conversion tracking cookie is set. Cookies are small text files that the Internet browser stores on the user's computer. These cookies lose their validity after 30 days and are not used for the personal identification of the users. If the user visits certain pages of this website and the cookie has not expired yet, Google and we can recognize that the user clicked on the ad and was redirected to this page.  
Each Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. The cookies can not be tracked through the websites of advertisers. The information gathered using the conversion cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Customers are told the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, they do not receive information that personally identifies users. If you do not wish to participate in tracking, you can opt-out of this use by disabling the Google Conversion Tracking cookie from your Internet browser under User Preferences. You will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. More information about Google AdWords and Google Conversion Tracking can be found in [Google's privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).  
You can set your browser so that you are informed about the setting of cookies and cookies only on a case by case basis, the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or generally exclude and can activate the automatic deletion of cookies when closing the browser. Disabling cookies may limit the functionality of this website. 

### Facebook Pixel

Our site uses the visitor action pixel from Facebook, Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave., Palo Alto, CA 94304 ("Facebook") for conversion measurement.   
This way, the behavior of the site visitors can be tracked after they have been redirected to the provider's website by clicking on a Facebook ad. As a result, the effectiveness of Facebook advertisements can be evaluated for statistical and market research purposes and future advertising measures optimized.  
The collected data are anonymous to us as the operator of this website, we can not draw conclusions about the identity of the users. However, the data are stored and processed by Facebook so that a connection to the respective user profile is possible and Facebook can use the data for its own advertising purposes, in accordance with the Facebook data usage directive. As a result, Facebook can enable ads to be displayed on Facebook and outside of Facebook. This use of data can not be influenced by us as the site operator. In the privacy policy of Facebook you will find more information on the protection of your privacy.  
You will find more information on the protection of your privacy in the [privacy policy of Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/).  
You can also disable the remarketing "Custom Audiences" feature in the Ads Settings section at [this link](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/). You have to be logged in to Facebook.  
If you do not have a Facebook account, you can opt out of use-based advertising from Facebook on the website of the [European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/de/praferenzmanagement/).  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Twitter Ads

We use services of the short message service Twitter. Twitter Ads is operated by Twitter Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107 ("Twitter"). Twitter allows us to use target group-based advertising, re-targeting and conversion measurements for online advertising via the so-called visitor interaction pixel. Here, offers for specific target groups are played out based on a selection of general criteria, such as demographic characteristics, regions or interests. Twitter also allows us to target ads based on your recent page views. For example, you may see ads and notices about our offers and content if you are interested in specific services, information, or offers at the online trade show. Here only general and technical information on accessed pages are evaluated. If you generally do not want to be tracked by Twitter, you can prevent the storage of cookies at any time by your browser settings, which could be limited function. Twitter is certified under the US-EU Privacy Shield, and is committed to complying with European privacy standards. Twitter also adheres to the do-not-track setting of their browser. More information can be found on the pages of Twitter.  
As a Twitter user, you can also prevent the data processing described by disabling the "Customize Ads Based on Affiliate Information" checkbox next to the "Sponsored Content" heading in the Security and Privacy settings. Further information can also be found on the pages of Twitter.  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Snapchat Ads

We use services of the short message service Snapchat. Snapchat Ads is operated by Snap Inc., 63 Market Street, Venice, CA 90291 ("Snapchat"). This pixel generates a hash from your usage data that is sent to Snapchat, such as browser information. If you have a Snapchat profile and you're logged in or logged in to Snapchat from one of your devices, you can then use the data provided by the pixels to showcase individualized advertising for our products and offerings on your devices across devices. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and how Snapchat processes and uses the data, as well as your privacy settings, see the [Snapchat Privacy Policy](https://www.snap.com/privacy/privacy-policy/).  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Outbrain Ads

Our website uses the technology of Outbrain Inc., 39 West 13th Street, 3rd floor, New York, NY 10011 ("Outbrain"), with which our users may be interested in further, possibly also interesting ones Contents within our website and on websites to be pointed out by third parties. Outbrain's integrated read recommendations are determined on a purely pseudonymous basis based on previous content read by the user. More information about Outbrain's privacy can be found [here](https://www.outbrain.com/legal/privacy). You can always object to tracking to show interest-based recommendations; Click on the "Decline" field (opt-out) under Outbrain's privacy policy.  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Taboola Ads

We use technologies from Taboola Inc., 28 West 23rd St. 5th Fl, New York, NY 10010 ("Taboola"). Taboola uses cookies that determine what content you use and which of our pages you visit. The cookie enables us to create pseudonymous usage profiles by collecting device-related data as well as log data and recommending content that suits your personal interests. So we can design our offer individually for you. These usage profiles do not allow you to draw conclusions about yourself. For more information about Taboola and the ability to disable the Taboola cookie, see [Taboola's privacy policy](https://www.taboola.com/privacy-policy) (opt-out information can be found under "Site Visitor Choices").  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Yahoo Gemini

We use Yahoo Gemini on our website, a marketing service provider operated by Oath (EMEA) Limited 5-7 Point Square, North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland. Yahoo Gemini supports the delivery of personalized and behavioral advertising over the Internet. The collection and storage of user information takes place anonymously and a conclusion to a natural person is not possible by using Yahoo Gemini. Yahoo Gemini uses cookies for this purpose, which can be deactivated at any time. The cookie can be deactivated under [this link](https://aim.yahoo.com/aim/us/en/optout/).  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Hubspot CM

We use HubSpot, a service of HubSpot Inc. (US based company based in Europe), 2nd Floor 30 North Wall Quay, Dublin 1, Ireland, on our analytical web pages. HubSpot is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. Here are used so-called "web beacons" and also "cookies" set, which are stored on your computer and allow an analysis of your use of the website by us. The collected information (eg IP address, geographical location, type of browser, duration of visit and pages accessed) is evaluated by HubSpot on behalf of us to generate reports about the visit and the visited pages of Blinkist. If you subscribe to e-mail news and / or use our services, with HubSpot we can also record your visits to Blinkist via your additional information (eg name / e-mail address) and, if necessary, target-oriented topics of your choice inform. If you generally do not want to be tracked by HubSpot, you can prevent the storage of cookies at any time by your browser settings. For more information about how HubSpot works, see [Hubspot Inc.'s Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy).  
Conversion cookies are stored on the basis of Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Adjust

We used the analysis technology of adjust GmbH, Saarbrücker Str. 36, 10405 Berlin; Tel: 49 (0) 30 91460083 ("Adjust"). Adjust collects and uses the IP address on our behalf and, if not disabled by the user in the system settings of its device, temporary device identification numbers. The information obtained in this way is only used to analyze the application, function and use of the app, for example, to determine which marketing measure users were aware of our app, ie concretely, which link or which banner users clicked before they downloaded our app.  
By using our app, you agree to the processing of anonymously collected data in the manner described above in the context of the stated purpose. You can also object to data collection and storage at any time with future effect by sending an e-mail to privacy@blinkist.com. 

### Hotjar

We use Hotjar, a web analytics service of Hotjar Ltd., St. Julian's Business Center, Elia Zammit Street 3, St Julian's STJ 1000 (Malta) ("Hotjar"). With Hotjar, interactions of randomly selected, individual visitors to our website are recorded anonymously. Logs of mouse movements and clicks, for example, are created from the recordings with the aim of making Blinkist even more intuitive and user-friendly. Hotjar also uses "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer. In order to exclude a personal relationship, IP addresses are stored only anonymously and information is processed only anonymously. It also provides information, including about your operating system | Browser | geographical origin (country), evaluated for statistical purposes. This information is not personal and will not be disclosed to third parties by us or by Hotjar.  
If you do not want your data to be tracked by Hotjar, just follow [this guide](https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out).  
For more information about Hotjar, see the Hotjar [Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy) and [Terms of Use](https://www.hotjar.com/terms). 

### Pinterest

We use services of the short message service Pinterest. Pinterest is operated by Pinterest Inc., 651 Brannan Street, San Francisco, CA 94103 (USA) ("Pinterest"). Pinterest allows us to use target group-based advertising, re-targeting and conversion measurements for online advertising via the so-called visitor interaction pixel. Here, offers for specific target groups are played out based on a selection of general criteria, such as demographic characteristics, regions or interests. Pinterest also allows us to target ads based on your recent page views. For example, you may see ads and notices about our offers and content if you are interested in specific services, information, or offers at the online trade show. Here only general and technical information on accessed pages are evaluated. If you generally do not want to be tracked by Pinterest, you can prevent the storage of cookies at any time by your browser settings, which could be limited function.  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### Quora

We use services of the short message service Quora. Quora is operated by Quora, Inc., 650 Castro Street, Suite 450, Mountain View, CA 94041 ("Quora "). Quora allows us to use target group-based advertising, re-targeting and conversion measurements for online advertising via the so-called visitor interaction pixel. Here, offers for specific target groups are played out based on a selection of general criteria, such as demographic characteristics, regions or interests. Quora also allows us to target ads based on your recent page views. For example, you may see ads and notices about our offers and content if you are interested in specific services, information, or offers at the online trade show. Here only general and technical information on accessed pages are evaluated. If you generally do not want to be tracked by Quora, you can prevent the storage of cookies at any time by your browser settings, which could be limited function.  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

### KeyWee

We use services of the short message service KeyWee. KeyWee is operated by Keywee Inc., 37 West 20th St, Suite 1010, New York, NY 10011 (USA) ("KeyWee "). KeyWee allows us to use target group-based advertising, re-targeting and conversion measurements for online advertising via the so-called visitor interaction pixel. Here, offers for specific target groups are played out based on a selection of general criteria, such as demographic characteristics, regions or interests. KeyWee also allows us to target ads based on your recent page views. For example, you may see ads and notices about our offers and content if you are interested in specific services, information, or offers at the online trade show. Here only general and technical information on accessed pages are evaluated. If you generally do not want to be tracked by KeyWee, you can prevent the storage of cookies at any time by your browser settings, which could be limited function.  
The storage of "conversion cookies" is based on Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in analyzing user behavior in order to optimize both its website and its advertising. 

## Newsletter

### Newsletter data

If you would like to receive the newsletter offered on the website, we need an e-mail address from you, as well as information that allows us to verify that you are the owner of the e-mail address provided and that you agree to receive the newsletter are. Further data are not collected or only on a voluntary basis. 

We use this data exclusively for the delivery of the requested information and do not pass it on to third parties. The processing of the data entered into the newsletter application form is based exclusively on your consent (Art.6 (1) (a) GDPR). Of course, you can revoke your consent to the storage of the data, the e-mail address and its use for sending the newsletter at any time, for example via the "unsubscribe" link in the newsletter. The legality of the already completed data processing operations remains unaffected by the revocation. 

The data deposited with us for the purpose of obtaining the newsletter will be saved by us from the newsletter until your cancellation and deleted after the cancellation of the newsletter or you will ensure that you will not receive any further newsletters ("blacklisting"). Data stored for other purposes with us (eg e-mail addresses for logging on to our services) remain unaffected. 

### MailChimp / Mandrill

This website uses the services of MailChimp for sending newsletters (or mandrill for sending information relevant to the user). Provider is the Rocket Science Group LLC, 675 Ponce De Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308 (USA). 

MailChimp is a service with which, among other things, the dispatch of newsletters can be organized and analyzed. If you have entered data for the purpose of newsletter subscription (eg e-mail address), these will be stored on the servers of MailChimp in the USA. 

MailChimp is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield is an agreement between the European Union (EU) and the United States designed to ensure compliance with European privacy standards in the United States. 

With the help of MailChimp we can analyze our newsletter campaigns. When you open an e-mail sent with MailChimp, a file included in the e-mail (called web beacon) connects to MailChimp's servers in the United States. This way you can determine if a newsletter message has been opened and which links have been clicked on. In addition, technical information is collected (eg time of retrieval, IP address, browser type and operating system). This information can be assigned to the respective newsletter recipient. They are used exclusively for the statistical analysis of newsletter campaigns. The results of these analyzes can be used to better tailor future newsletters to the interests of the recipient. 

If you do not want to be analyzed by MailChimp, you have to unsubscribe from the newsletter. For this purpose, we provide a link in every newsletter message. Furthermore, you can unsubscribe from the newsletter directly on the website. 

The data processing takes place on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 (1) a DSGVO). You can revoke these at any time by unsubscribing from the newsletter. The legality of the already completed data processing operations remains unaffected by the revocation. 

The data deposited with us for the purpose of obtaining the newsletter will be saved by us from the newsletter until you receive it and will be deleted from our servers as well as from the servers of MailChimp after cancellation of the newsletter. 

For details, see the [privacy policy of MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/). 

### Completion of a Data Processing Agreement 

We have entered into a so-called "Data Processing Agreement" with MailChimp, in which we commit MailChimp to protect the data of our customers and not to disclose them to third parties. This contract can be viewed at [this link](https://mailchimp.com/legal/forms/data-processing-agreement/sample-agreement/). 

### Payment Information

When you make payments for our services, no credit or debit card information is stored on our servers. This information is stored by our third party PCI-compliant payment processing companies. We work with the following providers: 

  * Recurly Inc., 400 Alabama Street Suite 202. San Francisco, CA 94110 (USA)
  * Stripe Inc., 185 Berry Street, Suite 550, San Francisco, CA 94107 (USA)

All credit and debit card transactions occur between the computer from which the transaction originates and our payment processor. When you use one of our trial phases or subscriptions or you purchase something through the service, credit card information and other financial information we need to process the payment is collected and stored with a payment service provider. We also collect certain limited information, such as your zip code, mobile phone number and details of your transaction history. In addition, these payment service providers usually provide us with very limited information about you, such as the unique "token", which enables you to make further purchases using the data stored by the service providers, as well as your card type, expiration date and last four digits of the number. 

### Completion of a data processing agreement 

We have concluded a so-called "Data Processing Agreement" with Recurly, in which we oblige the payment service provider to protect the data of our customers and not to pass them on to third parties. 

##  Candidate data privacy 

**Last updated: 01. June 2018**

Blinkist’s application management system is a service of Blinks Labs GmbH. 

The protection and legally correct collection, processing, and use of your personal data are important for us. In order for you to feel safe when completing and sending us your online application, we comply with all legal data protection requirements when handling your application. By sending us your application data, you consent to the Blinks Labs GmbH storing your data. 

Please read the following information about our data protection regulations: 

### 1\. RESPONSIBLE ENTITY

The entity responsible for collecting, processing, and using your personal data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is the Blinks Labs GmbH, Sonnenallee 223, 12059 Berlin, Germany. 

###  2\. COLLECTING, PROCESSING, AND USING YOUR PERSONAL DATA 

####  2.1 PERSONAL DATA 

Personal data means any information about material or personal circumstances of a specific and identifiable natural person. This includes, but is not limited to your name, your telephone number, your address, as well as all application data that you share with us in the course of your application. 

####  2.2 COLLECTING, PROCESSING, AND USING PERSONAL DATA 

For the purposes of managing your online application, we will collect, process, and use your personal data that you have disclosed to us via the online application form. With the exception of the mandatory fields marked with asterisks, you decide yourself which data you are willing to enter and share with us. The mandatory fields include your first name and last name, email address, resume, cover letter. 

Your data will be transmitted to the People & Organization department in charge and used exclusively for the purposes of the application process. This also includes using the data to contact you. Your data will not be disclosed to any third party – other than in the context of data processing commissions, especially those mentioned in section 2.3 – without your express consent. 

Your data will be transmitted to our People & Organization department. We are also happy to pass on your application to other persons in charge of departments with vacancies or other functional areas that fit your applicant profile. Please notify us if you do not consent to this. 

####  2.3 STORING OF YOUR APPLICATION DATA BY GOOGLE HIRE 

For our application management we use the services of Google Hire, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. For this purpose, your data is being stored and processed on servers of Google Hire, located in the USA. The storage is happening within the framework of a data processing agreement. Google Hire was selected with due care and assured us to fully respect applicable data protection rules. 

###  3\. DELETING PERSONAL DATA 

Your data will usually be deleted automatically after the end of the application process. You can always request us to delete your data by sending a mail to: privacy@blinkist.com. Please note that doing so means that you are withdrawing from any still on-going application processes. 

###  4\. TALENT POOL 

Upon invitation by our recruiting team, you have the option to agree to the storage of your personal data for our talent pool after the completion of the application process. Should you wish to use that option, your application data will be stored by us for a period of 12 months. After the end of the 12-month period, your application data will be deleted. You can always request us to delete the stored data by sending a mail to privacy@blinkist.com. 

###  5\. CONTACT FORM AND ZENDESK 

We use the Zendesk ticket system to handle applicant inquiries, a customer service platform of Zendesk Inc., 989 Market Street #300, San Francisco, CA 94102 (USA). Zendesk is a certified participant of the so-called "Privacy Shield Framework" and thus meets the minimum requirements for legally compliant order data processing. For more information about Zendesk's data processing, please refer to the Zendesk Privacy Policy. If you have questions, you can also contact the Privacy Officer of Zendesk directly. 

If you send us inquiries via contact form or by using our public, non-personal email addresses, your details from the inquiry form, including the contact details given there, will be stored with us for processing the request and in case of follow-up questions. We will not share this information without your consent. 

The processing of the data entered into the contact form is therefore exclusively based on your consent (Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR). You can revoke this consent at any time. An informal message by e-mail to us or our data protection officer is sufficient. The legality of the data processing operations carried out until the revocation remains unaffected by the revocation. 

The data entered by you in the contact form will remain with us until you request us to delete, revoke your consent to the storage or the purpose for the data storage is omitted (eg after completion of your request). Mandatory statutory provisions - especially retention periods - remain unaffected. 

###  6\. RIGHT TO INFORMATION / CONTACT 

In accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you have a right to be informed about all your personal details stored by us and, where applicable, a right to request their amendment, blocking, or deletion. 

We take the protection of your personal data very seriously. Please send your requests by email or post with proof of identity to our data protection officer Thorsten Schröers:   
HC Plus   
Geneststraße 5   
D-10829   
Berlin   
privacy@blinkist.com
